and looking at building more dams which
you know students they're one of the
suggestions and has been learned before
you starting at Ralph's to put any water
in this dams you maybe need 40 50 60
millimetres of fairly constant later
drained well if you would look at much
more but it falls on your roof will be
living and you have tanks and can tanks
come in all shapes these days you could
actually accept the considerable
percentage of responsibility right there
you use it and I think that will become
it's becoming very popular in Australia
we used to be dependent on Draenor the
tanks not there many years ago they were
banned in some suburban areas for quite
some years and today local government
gives bonuses or subsidies for people to
establish the tanks again so I think
it's more of a problem in people's mind
rather than a real problem there is less
rain pert climbs have about a reduction
of about 20 percent rainfall in the last
20 25 years and that's true for other
areas as well but is enough definitely
enough for the needs of urban areas or
suburban areas agriculture will have to
change in I grow food I'm a fireman and
no sort of to overhead irrigation
systems which you see have a a very
small place these days or flood
irrigation it's probably something which
we should see on photo is not in reality
anymore the irrigation system today
which can fulfill the need of irrigation
pipe unsatisfactory but without the need
for the same amount of water which other
irrigation systems need and some crops
in the case of Australia we should not
grow any more I mean I still do grow
rice so cotton same survey
crazy and finally you've also been
involved in some more mainstream design
projects as a consultant these you see
there's a potential of bringing some of
the design lessons from eco-village
design into the creation of new towns
and new sub obvious and this is still
going on and do we have a contribution
to make a memory yeah I'm convinced we
have to know the figures which are being
presented to us now showed that we need
to reduce our energy needs by 80 90 90
percent of what the current uses in the
north in the Western world I think we
need to look at each aspects of our
lives but that I mean food us through
this will be the highest energy user to
be shipping it around such long
distances I think education is a big
part to play in suburban urban
environments and the veinous of what is
possible and on small spaces like I
mentioned with vegetable growing with
energy there are some technical
solutions but no to replace call five
houses power stations with photovoltaics
I don't think it is really the solution
either we need to reduce our needs and
some of that will include technical
solutions some of these lifestyle
changes rather than just throwing our
clothes into a dryer which some people
apparently do there is actually an
excellent trial called the Sun which we
could should use and are many in the
examples too but technology will have a
part to play there too in the case of
water collection I mentioned some
examples and also in the case of
situation of waste water or what they
call waste water as we need to have a
paradigm shift as I see human excrement
of the diesels are rather that problem
if they combine this
and using design and technology in the
fireplace I reckon our quality of life
will be higher or have more social
interactions having will be much higher
much happier then many people are at the
moment and they can very much reduce our
impact on the environment unarmed energy
requirements
I think the future can be very bright if
we are preparing us ourselves for that
changes in energy costs and energy of
our delivery thank you very much thank
you